好了 同志們 你們可以考慮涂一下防曬霜
Okay, folks, you might want to put on some sunscreen.
這里海拔高 樹木都開始變得稀疏了
Up this high, the trees start to thin out.
這兒可能挺適合拍照的
Oh, this might be a good place for a picture.
容我去一下那塊石頭后面
Oh, let me go behind that rock.
我要換上我的下一套造型
I'll change into my next look.
又一套
Another one?
沒辦法 他照片分享網的粉絲要求的
He has to. His Instagram follower demands it.
老鷹
Eagle!
不對 假警報
Oh, wait, false alarm.
只是樹上的一個塑料袋
It's just a plastic bag in a tree.
老鷹啊
Eagle!
不是 抱歉
Nope. Sorry.
袋子掉下來了
Bag fell.
每年冬天
Every winter,
我都要和兄弟們一起來個觀鳥之旅...
I take a bird-watching trip with my buddies --
專門去看白頭鷹[美國國鳥]
specifically to see a bald eagle.
目前為止 還沒見到過
So far, no luck.
今年兄弟們來不了 不是背部抽筋 就是屁股開花
This year, my buddies bailed -- back spasm, cracked hip.
當初裝淋浴防滑椅時 誰笑我白癡來著
And I'm the idiot for installing a shower chair.
我本打算一個人去
I was all set to go solo,
結果這三個粘人精不請自來
when those three tagalongs invited themselves.
他們像一群栗胸森鶯一樣
They invaded my territory
侵入了我的領土
like a bunch of bay-breasted warblers.
我難道感覺不到自己像一只栗胸森鶯
Darned if I didn't feel like a bay-breasted warbler
闖入杰的旅途嗎 可歌洛莉亞非讓我們來
horning in on Jay's trip, but Gloria made us go.
她很擔心我爸
She was worried about my dad
這么大年紀了還一個人在林子里轉悠
being out in the woods alone at his age,
所以她輕輕地推了我們一把 讓我們加入
so she -- she gently nudged us to join him.
歌洛莉亞 如果我爸不想讓我們...
Gloria, if my dad doesn't want us t--
爸爸 你這周末要干什么去呀
Hey, Dad, uh, whatcha doin' this weekend?
-小小的自然之旅 -聽起來很有趣啊
- Ah, little nature trip. - Oh! Sounds like fun.
-帶上我們吧 -沒錯
- Count us in! - Yes.
其實我本來打算獨處一...
Actually, I was looking for a little alone time --
我是唯一一個腦子里想到白頭鷹的人嗎
Hey! Am I the only one with bald eagles on the brain?
你知道嗎 我想大約10分鐘后
You know what? I think in about 10 minutes,
光線會很完美
the light's gonna be perfect
適合拍我的"下午冒險"造型
for my "Afternoon Adventurer" look.
好了 在我們走入森林更深處之前
Okay, uh, before we head deeper into the woods,
我要警告你們 這片區域
I should warn you folks that there's been
有著多次目擊熊出沒的記錄
several bear sightings in the area.
-如果你們恰好帶了食物的話 -明白
- So if you happen to have any food with you -- - Got it!
我正想說
I was going to say
你們可以存在防熊箱里... 就在這兒
you can store it in this bear box... here.
好的
Oh. Um, okay.
那么 你們自己先聊會兒天
Well, then, talk amongst yourselves.
我可能要花一會兒時間
It could take me a while
才能找回被我陽剛之力丟遠的沉重背包...
to find where my manly heave sent that heavy --
在這兒呢 肯定是有人把它扔回來了
Ah! Here it is. Someone must've heaved it back.
謝謝
Thank you!
有人嗎
Hello!
歌洛莉亞 謝謝你能來
Oh, hey, Gloria. Thanks for coming.
這個女生之夜肯定會很有趣的
It's gonna be such a fun girls' night --
喝著酒 規劃著育兒室
drinking wine, planning the nursery.
好了 我本來是要給你驚喜的
Okay, I was going to surprise you,
但我等不及了
but I can't wait anymore.
這是個由歷史上偉大女性組成的手工床鈴
It's a handmade mobile of great women in history!
埃莉諾·羅斯福[美總統羅斯福的夫人]
Eleanor Roosevelt,
羅莎·帕克斯[拒絕給白人讓座的黑人女性]
Rosa Parks!
我只希望它能契合
I just hope it goes with the theme
迪蘭希望的房間主題
that Dylan wants for the room.
這些女性有沒有在消防車
Are any of these women important in the fields
或是獨角獸方面有杰出成就的
of fire trucks or unicorns?
這多完美啊
How perfect is this?
他們送來了嬰兒床
They delivered the crib,
我知道在場剛好有一隊手工能手們
and I know just the crew of handy honeys
會幫我把它組裝起來的
to help me put it together.
現在不行 媽媽 我今天過得很糟糕
Uh, not now, Mom. I've had the worst day.
我也是
Me, too.
快點 擠點淚出來
Quick, start crying.
我們得盡快澆滅她的熱情 趕在...
We need to derail her enthusiasm before she s--
太晚了
Unh! Too late.
她已經開始跳了
She's dancing.
太棒了 姐妹們
Way to rock it, girlfriend!
我無法再否認下去了
I cannot deny it anymore.
我變得越來越像白種女人了
I am turning into a white woman.
有什么問題嗎 姐妹們
Is there a problem, girlfriends?
單車課程取消了
Spin class was canceled!
不是吧
No!
那我們今天要干什么呢
What are we gonna do with our day?
"困惑時...
"When In Doubt...
就吃早午餐"
Brunch."
最近的一處賣羽衣甘藍
Where's the nearest place that serves kale
并且店名里有雙關語的地方在哪里
and also has a pun in its name?
這條街的盡頭有一家地下甘藍路餐廳
There's an Underground Kale-Road down the street!
-我們走 -感謝上帝
- Let's go! - Thank God.
我最近變得軟弱了
I've gotten soft lately.
我想我已經失去了哥倫比亞魂
I think I've lost my Colombian edge.
我想如果我們做成一件事 就能振奮起來
I think we'll all feel better if we accomplish something.
是啊 不像杰
Yes. Unlike Jay.
他去這些打獵旅行已經有二十年了
He's been going on these hunting trips for 20 years,
而他一次也沒有獵回白頭鷹過
and not once has he brought home a bald eagle!
天哪
Oh, God.
亨德里克斯[著名電吉他演奏者]不識譜
Hendrix couldn't read music,
沙克[籃球明星]罰球很爛
Shaq couldn't make free throws,
而我想象空間與大小的能力很差
and I have a little trouble visualizing space and scale.
這個衣柜設計可以在緊湊的住宅空間中
So, I think this closet design gives us everything we need
提供我們所需的全部功能
in a tight, residential space.
是啊 很巧妙
Yeah. Very clever.
演練一下
Take a walk-through.
看看動線是不是合理
Does the flow make sense?
好吧
Well, um...
我會在洗完澡后
I would get out of the shower
把衣服扔進這里的衣籃
and throw my clothes in the hamper here,
拿一件衣服 然后在這里著裝完畢
pick out an outfit, and then get dressed right here.
你剛剛把你的衣服扔進了壁爐
You just threw your clothes in the fireplace
然后在落地窗前穿好衣服
and got dressed in front of the picture window.
你有你早晨起床的方式 米婭
Well, you have your morning routine, Mia.
我也有我的嘛
I have mine.
好了 讓我們看一遍
All right, let's get this over with.
媽媽 我們從哪兒開始呢
Mom, where do we start?
也許老娘需要一點熟女汁[酒]
Maybe Mommy just needs some cougar juice!
我這是怎么了
What's wrong with me?
大家注意腳下
Watch your step, folks.
徒步走到這一段路的時候
Some of the terrain gets a little tricky
有的地形就不太好走了
on this part of the hike.
真好 我還以為我換
Oh. Good. I thought I'd changed
"路遙啟程"裝換早了
into my "Remote Trailhead" look too soon.
你還行嗎 爸 要不要停下來休息一會
You okay, Dad? Want to stop and take a break?
不 不用 我就是想停下來看看有沒有鷹
No, no. I just want to stop and maybe see an eagle. Ah.
大家看看吧
Everybody look.
你徒步了二十年都沒見過一只鷹 是嗎
You've been doing this for 20 years and never seen one, huh?
是的 噓
Correct. Shh.
是啊 大自然有時候真的很...
Yeah. Mother Nature can be a real --
菲爾 別說話了
Phil, stop talking!
你把鷹都嚇跑了
You're scaring the eagles!
對不起
I'm sorry.
我的錯 我的錯
My bad. My bad.
我真誠地對不起
Also sorry in my head.
真是的
Oh, my God!
趁著大家在聊天 我們應該往回走了
Since we're talking again, uh, we should start heading back.
天很快就會黑了
It'll be dark soon.
或者 你們愿意的話 這條小路前面有個小木屋
Or, if you'd like, there's a cabin just up this trail.
有點陳舊 不過...
It's pretty run-down, but, uh,
你們可以在那里過夜
you're welcome to spend the night.
我要去
I'll do it.
這不太像個好主意啊
Uh... Are -- Are we sure that's a good idea?
不是說有熊嗎
Um...wasn't there -- wasn't there mention of bears?
不用 你回家吧 我自己留在這里
No, you go home. I'll stay by myself.
我們不能讓他一個人過夜
We -- We can't let him stay by himself.
我們跟歌洛莉亞保證過他的安全
We told Gloria we'd keep him safe.
是啊 要是他要留下來 我們也要留下來
Yeah, if he's staying, we're staying.
好吧 好吧 最壞能壞到哪去呢
Yeah. Yeah. What -- What's the worst that could happen?
想想電影里城里人在廢棄的小木屋過夜
I mean, in the movies, when city folk stay overnight
通常都是平平安安 絕對沒有殺人魔
in abandoned cabins, things usually pan out okay.
不管了 我要到前面去看看
Anyway, I'm gonna run ahead, see if they have any postcards
這個安保糟糕的精神病院有沒有明信片
up at this poorly guarded mental institution.
靠 我要餓死了
Damn it, I'm starving.
這里除了一瓶舊威士忌什么都沒有
Nothing in here but an old bottle of whiskey.
不要一直想著你有多餓或者想著
Well, just try not to think about how hungry you are
米奇爾把吃的都放在防熊箱里了
or that Mitchell left the food in the bear box.
我們都把食物放在...
We all left the food in the --
你又換衣服了嗎
Did you change again?
是啊 我又混搭了幾件
Yeah, I just threw a few things together
來了一套"鄉間小屋"裝
to create a "Rustic Cabin" look.
至少不用擔心熊的問題
Well, at least the bears won't be a concern.
信我這個房產經紀人的話
Take it from a realtor.
這把史密斯威利鎖可是上好品質
This Smith & Wiley lock is the gold standard.
好了 我覺得我們現在可以拼起
All right, I think we are now ready to put together
我們漂亮的L形嬰兒床了
our beautiful, L-shaped crib.
這不對啊 一邊比另一邊大太多了
I-I-- This can't be right. One's way bigger.
而且 我的寶寶要像在中繼之家一樣
And what, my babies are supposed to come and go as they please,
想來就來想走就走嗎
like they're in a halfway house?
好吧 稍微有點看錯了圖紙
Um, so, a minor misreading of the diagram.
我覺得我們把長邊和短邊
I think we're just gonna need to swap
換一下位置
a short side for a long side.
同時再把支架折彎就可以了
And in the meantime, we bent that bracket.
艾麗克斯 你能去趟五金店嗎
Alex, would you mind running down to the hardware store?
不可能
No way.
我不相信自己的開車技術了
I don't trust myself to drive anymore.
我報名當了一個學校訪問學者的
I signed up to be the student liaison
學生聯絡員
for a visiting scholar on campus --
肯尼斯·彭羅斯先生
Sir Kenneth Penrose.
是的 大名鼎鼎的肯尼斯·彭羅斯先生
Yes, that Sir Kenneth Penrose.
微生物學界的搖滾明星啊
Rock star of the microbiology world.
我知道你可能都要聽膩了
I know you must hear this a lot,
但你是我開始打臺球的原因
but you're the reason I took up snooker.
你還有打嗎
Do you still play?
最近我不得不放下臺球
I've had to lay down my cue lately.
這幾個月我一直在研究埃博拉疫苗
I've been working for months on an Ebola vaccine.
就在剛剛 我有了重大突破
Just moments ago, I had a breakthrough.
我簡直等不及去實驗室記下
I can't wait to get to the lab and jot --
那是我的化學老師
Whoa! That was my chemistry advisor.
我可不希望自己出名是因為
I would not want to be known as the girl who --
肯尼斯先生
Sir Kenneth?
我在哪
W-Where am I?
你不知道有多羞愧
You don't know the shame.
現在除了像社會學教授那樣的笨蛋
Now they won't let me drive around
他們誰都不讓我載了
anyone smarter than a sociology professor.
你知道今天還有誰摔地上了嗎 我
You know what else hit the ground today? Me.
就在我彎腰撿地板上的甜甜圈的時候
While I was bending over to pick up a doughnut off the floor!
上面沾了好多灰 不過我不在乎
It was covered in dust balls, but I didn't care,
因為我是個惡心的大豬怪
'cause I'm a disgusting pig monster.
寶貝 別這么說
Oh, honey, please.
你還是像
You're as --
以前一樣漂亮
as beautiful as ever.
跟"臉部解鎖"說去吧
Tell that to MugScan.
那是我上班的地方用的一個人臉識別軟件
MugScan is a face-recognition program we use at work.
那軟件對我很不友好
It was really mean to me.
早上好 韋恩
Good morning, Wayne.
韋恩
Wayne?
我才不是韋恩 你個大混蛋
I'm not Wayne, you jerk!
你沒事吧 海莉
You all right, Haley?
我沒事 韋恩
I'm fine, Wayne.
我摔倒的時候一只鞋掉了
One of my shoes flew off in the fall,
而我都穿不回去 因為我的腳太腫了
and I couldn't put it back on because my feet were so swollen.
你知道誰做鞋做得好嗎 新百倫
You know who makes a great shoe? New Balance.
我快走去看尼爾·戴蒙德[歌手]的時候就穿這鞋
I wear them when I power-walk to Neil Diamond.
媽 這個隔板是不是有點高
Hey, Mom, is this divider a little too high?
沒有啊 就應該是那樣的
No. No, it's supposed to be that way.
那樣的話 要是一個寶寶想去看他的兄弟
That way, if one twin wants to visit the other,
他就可以噠噠噠走過來"你好呀"
he can just go, "Ah, doot, doot, doot. Hi!"
我有點小想法
Couple thoughts.
對七 對A
Pair of 7s. Ace high.
大家好 讓你們見見多恩·萊蒙和魯保羅
Everyone, I'd like you to meet Don Lemon and RuPaul,
一對黑皇后[黑人騷基]
a pair of black queens.
米奇爾 這都是你第三次晃蕩到那兒了
Mitchell, that's the third time you've wandered over there.
你在那干什么呢
What are you doing?
-沒什么 -他嘴里有東西
- Nothing. - He's got something in his mouth.
-抓住他 過來 -沒 我沒吃
- Get him! come here! - No. No, I don't.
-別 別 -別反抗
- No, no, no! - Don't -- Don't fight. Don't --
他有牛肉干
He has beef jerky!
這是最后一塊了 我發誓
That's the last of it. I swear.
-他撒謊 檢查口袋 -沒有 我
- He's lying. Check his pockets. - No, I --
住手 住手
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
是家庭裝的
It's a family pack!
我希望牛肉干[混蛋]的滋味和這諷刺一樣足
I hope the jerky was as delicious as the irony.
-交出來 -不 停手 停手
- Give it! - No, stop it! Stop it --
不
No!
太好了 我們給滿森林的熊
Great. We're sending beef smoke signals
發了牛肉味信號
to a forest full of bears.
對不起 我本該分享的
I'm sorry! I should've shared!
與此同時 有滿滿一背包的遠足零食
Meanwhile, there is a sack full of hiking snacks
就在路那頭
just up the road!
干酪 熏火腿
Brie, prosciutto,
更別提還有歌洛莉亞在品趣志上推薦的
not to mention a wonderful maple-walnut butter
美味的楓糖核桃味黃油
that Gloria recommended on her Pinterest board.
我受夠了 我要出去
That's it. I'm going out there.
杰 等等
Jay, wait!
假如你看到了熊 記住
If you see a bear, remember --
用手機上的手電筒晃他
blind it with the flash on your phone,
然后用順從的姿勢躺到地上
then lie on your back in a submissive pose.
我不會那么做的 假如我和熊迎頭碰上
I'm not doing that. If I come face-to-face with a bear,
它最好逃命去
he better run!
外面好黑
It's darker out there --
你確定這主意好嗎
Are you sure it was the best idea
不該先搬到樓上再組裝嗎
to attach these before moving them upstairs?
我肉眼量過 應該能輕松通過
Yeah, I eyeballed the space. It really should fit easily.
只不過艾麗克斯把我們"開進死胡同"了
Except Alex apparently has steered us into a jam.
肯定是送披薩的 我來了 卡爾
Oh, that must be the pizza guy. Coming, Carl!
你知道送披薩的叫什么嗎
You know the pizza guy's name?
才不知道
No!
海莉
Hey, Haley.
真驚訝 你居然在午夜前點披薩
Surprised to get an order from you before midnight.
對了 上次那個
By the way, how'd you like
特別定制的蝦薯披薩好吃嗎
that custom shrimp and potato pizza?
我根本不知道你在胡說什么
I don't even know what you're talking about.
愛死了 也愛死你了
Loved it. Love you.
我去拿錢包
Gonna go get my wallet!
媽
Mom?
好吧
Okay.
艾麗克斯 快去樓下拿個螺絲刀
Alex, run downstairs and get a screwdriver.
等我們把柵欄拆了就能輕松通過了
This whole thing will fit easily once we take the cribs apart.
我們根本不知道
We don't even know
這東西能不能通過臥室門
if this thing is gonna fit through the bedroom door.
當然能通過
Of course it will.
但要是能讓你高興 我再量一次
But if it makes you happy, I will measure again.
瞧
See?
你總把我錄的節目覆蓋...
You always record over my programs --
好吧 這樣如何
Okay, no, how about this?
我們圍在一起組成一個大塊頭
We all band together to form one big man
去拿吃的
to go get the food.
不 這怎么能行得通
No! How's that supposed to work?
-背靠背 胳膊挽起來 -拜托
- Okay, back to back, um, and-and then link arms. - Come on.
-好吧 -轉過來 胳膊伸過來
- Okay. - Turn around, give me your arm.
瞧 就像這樣 明白嗎
See, look? Like this, all right?
我們看起來塊頭很大很可怕吧
Do we look big and scary?
我想是的
Well, I think so.
我們朝門移動
Let's move towards the door.
好
Okay.
慢慢來
Nice and easy.
我們是一個要去林間散步的大塊頭
We're just one big man out for a walk in the woods.
分散
Scatter!
活下來了
We made it.
等等 米奇爾在哪
Wait! Where's Mitchell?
他沒成功逃脫
He didn't make it!
你們兩個人之一得去找他
One of you two need to go get him!
我最好留在這做熊誘餌
I'm better staying here as a bear decoy.
我身上自帶麝香味
I give off a natural musk.
總有鳥落在我身上 松鼠也從我手里吃食
Birds land on me all the time. Squirrels eat out of my hand.
我不能去 不能讓莉莉雙父雙亡
Well, I can't go! Lily needs at least one living parent!
等等
Wait!
我們怎么知道來的不是熊
How do we know it's not the bear?
是我
It's me!
你們把我拋下了
You just left me!
你也沒在外面多久
Oh, you weren't out there that long.
你沒把吃的拿來嗎
You didn't get the food?!
我差點成吃的了
I almost was food!
我真希望壓根沒參加這破遠足
Okay, I-I wish I never even came on this stupid trip!
誰逼你來的
Well, who forced you?
歌洛莉亞
Gloria!
我是靠這腳脖子送披薩的
It's my delivery ankle.
真的傷得很重 大伙
It's really bad, dudes.
本來就有漆彈射擊的舊傷 卡爾
It was already weak from your paintball injury, Carl.
我叫你去看醫生了
I told you to get it checked out,
可你就是討厭醫生
but you and doctors.
好吧 我跟他有點交情
Okay, fine, I know him a little.
禍不單行 對吧
When it rains, it pours, huh?
瑪格利特-安今早跟我分手了
Margaret-Anne left me this morning.
然后我爸又在電話里叫我"克雷格"
Then my dad called me "Craig" On the phone again.
那是他新兒子的名字
That's the name of his new son.
天哪 卡爾 至少讓我們送你回家吧
Oh, God. Carl, can we at least drive you home?
還不行
Not now.
我得給勁敵西格瑪兄弟會送十張披薩
I have 10 pizzas going to my enemies, the Sigmas.
那些富二代利用"30分鐘沒送到就免費"政策
Those rich kids get their kicks taking advantage
占我們便宜 覺得很過癮
of our "30 Minutes or it's Free" Policy --
用所有小把戲拖慢我的速度
use every trick in the book to slow me down.
今晚沒門 查德和奇普
Well, not tonight, Chad and Chip.
今晚沒
Not to-
骨頭肯定支出來了 對嗎
The bone's got to be sticking out, right?
沒有 腫都沒腫
No, it's not even swollen.
卡爾 我們今天都很不順
Look, Carl, we've all had rough days.
何不讓我們幫你把披薩送到
Why don't you let us finish this delivery for you?
好 可我們只剩十分鐘了
Okay, but we've only got, like, 10 minutes.
那我們走 過來
Let's go, then! Come here.
-好 -快來
- Okay. - Come on!
今天完成一項任務會感覺很好的
It'll feel good to get something right today.
再說 我不介意
Plus, I wouldn't mind
收拾幾個兄弟會的白人小混蛋
sticking it to some preppy, white jerks.
白人也有白人的煩惱
Hey! That life comes with its own problems!
別生氣 爸
Don't be mad, Dad.
歌洛莉亞也是擔心你嘛
Gloria was just worried about you.
我不想談這事
I don't want to talk about it.
我們就靜靜地喝一杯吧
Let's just have a drink and be quiet.
那火焰呈現出很多種顏色 對吧
Lot of colors in that fire, huh?
紅 綠
Red, green...
-黃 藍... -老天 夠了
- yellow, blue... - Geez. Okay.
你怎么老是逼逼個不停 干嘛呢
What is this yammering with you?! Seriously!
我不知道
I don't know.
可能我不喜歡與自己的思緒獨處吧
I guess I just don't like being alone with my own thoughts.
又或者是因為我有兩個外孫快出生了
Maybe it's because I have a couple of grandkids on the way,
但現在 如果周圍太安靜了
but now, if -- if things get too quiet,
我就會開始胡思亂想
my mind goes to a dark place fast.
開始擔心我愛的人
I start to worry about the people that I love
害怕他們會遭遇什么不測
and all the bad things that could happen to them.
可能我內心覺得說話.... 會趕走那些念頭
I suppose talking... pushes those thoughts out
讓我平靜下來
and helps me feel okay.
我懂
I get it.
我們都有充滿負能量的時候
We can all spiral.
但你不能用說話來解決
But you can't talk your way out of it.
而是得通過思考
You got to think your way out of it.
想象一個讓自己快樂的地方
You know, find a happy place.
試試這樣
Try this.
30秒 不說話 開始
30 seconds, no talking. Go.
-兄弟 你神游到哪去了 -我回來了
- Buddy, where are you? - I'm back. Yep.
我認為我們能從他身上學到很多
You know, I think we can learn a lot from this guy,
因為我們害怕的
because it's not the --
不是外面的熊
the bears out there that we're afraid of.
而是我們生活中的"熊"
It's the bears in our lives --
讓我們夜不能寐
the fear that keeps us up at night.
這個話題很有趣 等我換上"爐邊談心"裝后
And I think that's an interesting topic we can return to
我們再繼續討論
once I change into my "Fireside Chat" Look.
又去換衣服
Another wardrobe change?
你就像婚禮當天的蘇丹新娘一樣 換裝個不停
You're like a sultan's bride on her wedding day.
繼續說吧 取笑我吧
Go ahead -- make fun of me.
我喜歡我的衣服
I like my outfits.
為什么要那么多
Why so many?
我想是因為我小的時候
Yeah, I guess when I was a kid,
我發覺自己永遠都無法融入大眾
I realized I wasn't ever gonna fit in,
于是我決定引人注目
so I decided to stand out.
我坦然接受了自己的浮夸騷氣
I embraced my flamboyance
好讓世人知道 他們的羞辱傷不了我
to let the world know their insults won't hurt me.
想開我玩笑嗎 盡管開 因為我會配合你
Want to make a joke about me? Go ahead, 'cause I'm in on it.
說得真好 小卡
That's really beautiful, Cam.
而且你不是一個人
And you're not alone.
誰小時候不是個沒安全感的書呆呢
Growing up, we were all insecure nerds in our own way.
我小時候很酷
I was cool.
怎么了 我們不是在分享內心故事嗎
What? I thought we were sharing.
你很勇敢 小卡 了不起
That's very brave, Cam. That's good stuff.
你瘋了嗎 不該由我來開車
Are you crazy?! I shouldn't be the one driving!
沒時間爭論了 開就是了 快點
There is no time to argue! Just go! Come on!
很感謝你們讓我加入你們
Thanks so much for making me part of your group.
不是每天都能交到四個新死黨的
It's not every day you make four new best friends.
他們為什么那么慢
Why are they going so slow?!
我沒法超過他們
I can't get past them!
這是西格瑪兄弟會的策略之一
This is one of Sigma's tactics.
他們用手機應用追蹤我所在地點
They track my location on the app
然后派想入會的人來拖慢我的速度
and send pledges to try to slow me down.
我該怎么辦
Ugh! What am I gonna do?!
我來搞定
I'll handle this.
卡爾 我要借用你的漆彈槍
Carl, I'm taking your paintball guns!
讓開 否則我打爆你們
Move! Or I move you!
我的哥倫比亞魂果然還在
I do still have my edge!
好棒
Yes!
你能加入我的漆彈隊伍嗎
Will you join my paintball team?
那是什么玩意
What is that?!
小黃人雷區 典型的西格瑪招數
Field of Minions. Classic Sigmas.
別被他們的可愛分心
Don't get distracted by the cuteness.
我們只剩下五分鐘
We only have five minutes.
直接繞過它們
Just go around them.
天啊 我做到了
Oh, my God, I did it!
你們都還在車上 沒人被甩出去
And you're all still in the car!
好了 我們不能讓他們找到借口
Okay, now, we can't give them any reason to say
趕快檢查披薩 確保配料沒移位
so check the pizzas, make sure they didn't shift.
海莉 我覺得你多慮了
Oh, Haley, I'm sure you're worrying about nothing --
卡爾 你有披薩切片器嗎
Carl, do you have a pizza slicer?
只有一個我為公司服務十年得到的紀念切片器
Only the commemorative one I got for 10 years of service.
給我 我腦中有畫面了
Give it to me. I have a vision.
奧尼爾和亨德里克斯從沒能突破自身弱點
Shaq and Hendrix never got past their blind spots.
也許是因為他們不夠渴望
Maybe they didn't want it enough.
想把九個披薩變成十個 很簡單
Turning 9 pizzas into 10 was a simple matter
只需從每個披薩切走一片
of removing one slice from each pie,
然后將剩下的披薩
then trimming off a V-shaped portion of pizza
每片都切走一小塊V型
from each of the remaining slices,
把切片從36°角變為40°角
turning them from 36-degree angles to 40-degree angles,
再把所有40°角的切片
then putting together the 40-degree angles
拼成九個小了一圈的披薩
into nine slightly smaller pies.
之后 再用一開始切出的九片披薩
After that, one had only to repurpose
拼出第十個披薩
the nine previously removed slices into a 10th pie.
十個
And...10!
成功了
It worked!
真的成功了
It really did.
我果然有圖像式腦子
I do have a visual brain.
這就是你糾結的事嗎
That was your thing?
我真不懷念有白人煩惱
I do not miss having white-people problems.
到了 我成功了
We're here! I did it!
得在一分鐘之內把披薩送進屋 走吧
We only have a minute to get the pizzas inside. Let's go!
等一下 等一下 兄弟會有可視門鈴
Oh, wait, wait, wait! Uh, the frat has a video doorbell.
他們如果看到是外賣 就會拖延到超時
If they see it's a delivery, they try to run out the clock.
我來搞定
I'll handle this.
靠那邊站
Stay on that side.
什么事
Yeah?
你好
Hi. Um...
我是A大的 人家醉得不行了
I go to U of A, and I'm super drunk.
你們有地方借我醒酒過夜嗎
Is there a place where I can sober up for the night?
至少老娘的臉還足夠美艷 能進入兄弟會的房子
At least my looks can still get me into a frat house.
好了 各位 上啊
Okay, guys, go, go!
十個披薩準時送達
10 pizzas on time.
付錢
Pay up!
你們跟卡爾是一伙的嗎
You guys with Carl?
我們就是卡爾
We are Carl.
來吧 快點 愿賭服輸
Come on, hurry up! A bet's a bet!
我就說我能比你們金雞獨立更久
I told you I could stand on one leg longer than you!
你是唯一一個喝完一大杯威士忌后
You're the only one whose balance gets better
平衡感反而比喝之前更好的人
after drinking a jug of whiskey.
好啦 我的粉絲一定會喜歡這畫面
All right. My follower is gonna love this!
大家說"茄子"
Everybody say "Cheese!"
-茄子 -很好
- Cheese. - Yes.
好啦 這就是建立起自我品牌的方法
Okay, now, that is how you build a brand.
看來我們應該繼續把剩下的威士忌喝完
Well, I guess we should kill the rest of this whiskey.
那殺人魔來的時候我們請人家喝什么啊
But then we'll have nothing to serve the murderers when they arrive.
雖然你漫不經心開玩笑
You know, you joke,
但你語氣里暗藏著某種偏執妄想
but you have a certain paranoia about you.
這... 背后到底是什么原因呢
What -- What's behind that?
這個嘛...
Well...
我們要聽到米奇爾心中的"熊"了嗎
Ooh! Are we about to hear about Mitchell's bear?
好吧 其實是...
Uh, okay. It -- It's, um...
我沒有跟任何人說過 但是...
I've never told anyone this, but, uh,
有個算命師曾經預言
a fortune teller once predicted
我活不到46歲的冬天
that I would not live to see my 46th winter.
是以前我們家隔壁的那個瘋子嗎
Was that that kook that used to live next door to us?
她是神經病啊
She's nuts.
她還說過你媽有一天會贏托尼獎呢
She told your mother she was gonna win a Tony one day.
但她也預言對了其他很多事情啊
But she was right about a lot of other things.
她說我會變成律師
She said that I'd become a lawyer.
她還說我有一天會跟一個小丑結婚
She said that I would marry a clown one day.
當時聽到我可是笑了好久
Laughed a long time about that one.
為什么要笑
Why?
總而言之 我內心的"熊"
Anyway, I-I guess my "Bear"
大概就是害怕英年早逝吧
is the fear of dying young.
如果那個算命師算得準
Uh, I mean, if that fortune teller's right,
那我只剩三年能活了
I only have three more years to live.
你知道嗎 按我來看
Well, y-you know what? The way I see it,
這個小小的詛咒是上天的禮物
this little curse is actually a gift --
讓你有理由充分享受人生
a reason to live life to the fullest.
也不給自己留下遺憾
And have no regrets.
行 大家都相信并接受我活不過46歲了
Okay, so we're all just accepting this 46-year thing as true?
我們能理性看待它
We've made our peace with it.
你也應該這樣
And so should you.
為什么不在你有限的日子里
Why not just live your limited days
做到心中不藏著任何話
with leaving nothing unsaid?
對你最在乎的人說出你的感受
Tell the people who matter the most how you feel.
我每天都跟你與莉莉說我愛你
I tell you and Lily I love you every single day.
的確 那對菲爾呢
True. What about Phil?
他今天早上也有發短信給我說"愛尼"
He did text me with a "Love ya" this morning.
也能算數
Close enough.
那你爸爸呢
And your dad?
你不是吧
Seriously?!
對他開口說這個詞很難嘛
I just have a hard time saying that word to him.
我個人對此也沒有意見
Which is fine for the both of us.
好吧 感覺起來
Okay, well, it sounds like
你也羞于說出這個詞
you might be uncomfortable with that word, too.
才沒有 我對這詞沒任何問題 我整天說
No! I don't have a problem with it. I use it all the time.
我整天都有在說我愛什么東西
I'm always saying I love things. I --
我愛穿上用微波爐熱過的溫暖襪子
I love the feel of toasty socks out of the microwave.
我愛聽遠方火車汽笛的聲音
I love the far-off sound of a train whistle.
會感覺"他們又去哪里冒險啦"
You know, "Ooh! What adventure have they gotten off to?"
我還愛看嬰兒伸懶腰
I -- I love watching a baby stretch.
杰 這些都是你生活中的美好事物 但...
Those are all good things in your life, Jay, but...
你的"熊"是什么
what's your "bear"?
我沒有啊
I don't have one.
別這樣 我們都說出自己的了
Oh, come on! We all told you ours.
等你們活到我這個歲數
Now, when you get to my age,
人生中能讓你害怕的事物就越來越少了
there are less things that you're afraid of.
除了或許...
Except maybe...
自己變成家人的累贅
being a burden to your family.
而這已經開始發生
Which is starting already,
因為歌洛莉亞逼你們來照顧我
because Gloria forced you guys to babysit me,
這也是為何我執意要在此過夜
which is why I wanted to spend the night here
好證明自己不是... 脆弱的糟老頭
so I could prove I'm not some...frail old man.
但如果要我實話實說
But, if I'm being honest,
每年爬上來都感覺比前一年更累了
that hike gets tougher for me every year.
我今年也慶幸我不是自己一個人爬
And I was relieved that I didn't have to do it alone.
老爸
Oh, Dad.
你永遠不會是累贅
You could never be a burden.
對啊 你才是總是照顧著我們大家的人
Yeah, you're the one who's always taking care of all of us.
我們很樂意有機會照顧你
We'd love the chance to return the favor.
好啦 時間晚了
All right. It's getting late.
這個山地皮條客裝穿到我流汗
This mountain pimp outfit's making me sweat.
大家... 大家都去睡了吧
Let's -- Let's get some rest.
晚安
Good night.
晚安啦 我睡沙發
Good night. I'll take the sofa.
你確定你自己睡這里沒問題嗎
Sure you're gonna be okay out here?
-當然啦 我肯定沒事 -好
- Yeah, I'll be fine. - Okay.
你... 你要不要我幫你多拿條被子還什么
Do -- Do you want me to grab you an extra blanket or something?
不 不用了 我需要會自己去拿
No, no. I'll get something if I need it.
好吧 那...
Okay. Well...
晚安啦
Good night.
我都知道
I know.
好啦 老爸 我們準備好走了
All right, Dad. We're ready to go.
對啊 杰
Yeah, Jay.
很遺憾你這次又沒有看到白頭鷹
I'm sorry you didn't see a bald eagle this time around.
是啊 太遺憾了
Y-Yeah. It's too bad.
看來我們只能明年再一起回來碰運氣了
I guess we'll all have to come back here again next year.
好啊
Yeah.
我不知道你們怎么樣 但我睡得好香
I don't know about you guys, but I slept great.
那個小床好軟 我平常很容易睡不好
That cot was so soft. I'm not always a sound sleeper.
本來還一直很想去試試吃褪黑素
Been meaning to try that melatonin.
我聽說超級有效呢
I hear it's a real game-changer.
現在那東西好像到處都有賣
And you can get it anywhere nowadays.
那東西一直都是非處方藥[柜臺外]嗎
Has it always been over-the-counter?
這詞挺有意思的對吧 "柜臺外面"
Kind of a funny phrase, isn't it -- "Over-the-counter"?